Who is Chen Xiaofang?
That's me.
Zhou Fang said you're very bossy.
Zhou Fang?
What's your relationship with him?
We're very closely related.
He has to call me Cousin Great-Grandaunt.
Great-Grandaunt?
And a cousin, at that?
Forgive my bluntness,
I haven't met many living great-grandaunts.
That's how big families are.
There are many branches.
You're just ignorant.
Miss Cousin Great-Grandaunt,
right this way, please.
Have a seat first.
This is our Duoduo.
I want to hold a grand funeral for him.
A crystal coffin.
A mountain of flowers.
A 24-person professional mourning team.
The urn must be a limited edition.
Pick a grave with excellent feng shui.
Feng shui?
A pet funeral?
That's impossible.
You must be joking.
I'm sorry,
Miss Cousin Great-Grandaunt.
You made this trip for nothing.
Our shop only handles funerals for people.
He was with me for over ten years.
How is he not family?
What a pity.
I prepared this 200,000 for nothing.
This 200,000...
Can't be spent here after all.
Please forgive the offense,
Miss Cousin Great-Grandaunt.
Please, take a seat.
Bro, go pour some water!
Let me explain our services to you in detail.
After all, dogs are man's best friend.
Your feelings are completely understandable.
Our Duoduo loves pink.
Even a dazzling pink works.
I want a gold-plated paper house.
Gold-plated and diamond-studded...
We can make that happen.
Do you think I'm dead?!
Our ancestors taught us to bury humans,
not to mourn an animal!
You're ruining our old shop's reputation!
If I'm ruining it, I'm using my money!
This little bit of money
won't ruin Xiaoxitian's reputation!
Is this enough?
As the saying goes, hang a dead cat on a tree,
and throw a dead dog in the river.
This is the rule left by our ancestors.
A funeral for a beast?
No amount of money will make it happen!
Oh, Dad!
I saw many animals age and die at the zoo.
In the end, they're no different from us.
Don't you always talk about respecting life?
A human's life is a life,
but isn't a dog's life a life too?
Aren't animal lives still lives?
Exactly!
Dad, you're being such a hypocrite.
Old man,
you might be an old fossil,
but your son and daughter are quite sensible.
Are you going to take this job or not?
It doesn't matter to me.
I can spend my money anywhere.
But I must hold a funeral for Duoduo.
The people my great-grandson Zhou Fang picked
must be the right choice.
Leaving Duoduo to you,
I feel completely at ease.
I'll leave the money with you for now.
Old man,
you should learn from your son.
Keep up with the times.
Take care, Miss Cousin Great-Grandaunt!
Take your money back!
Dad, forget it.
No, no, no!
I...
If any of you takes this funeral job today,
I'll disown you!
It's 200,000!
Brother Jianguo,
"Who says creatures' lives don't matter?
They have the same flesh and skin as us."
Animals...
How can they be compared to humans?
Here you go.
Here.
Thanks, Uncle Daren.
No problem.
Uncle Daren's treating today.
Uncle Daren.
I've got a lot of money now.
Just let me splurge a bit.
Alright.
The beers will be on me, alright?
Deal.
I'll have ten chicken hearts.
You got it.
Order whatever you like.
Alrighty.
Thanks, Uncle Daren.
Today,
with this first glass,
I want to toast my dear brother.
If it weren't for your impassioned speech,
this deal would've probably fallen through.
Chen Baixi,
Rich ladies really have a thing for you.
You know what,
She might've chased him here from Beijing.
So tell me, along the way,
how many girls has he messed around with?
You two sure can make up stories.
Actually,
Besides out-of-towners, there's a local.
Who?
Fan Shiqi.
Miss Fan.
Right, right.
There's her too.
Li Yiran,
you care so much about me,
could it be that you're jealous?
Are you two secretly dating behind my back?
No way.
I'm not a rich woman.
Your brother wouldn't go for me.
You're right.
Anyway, for today's order,
I'm definitely taking it.
The principle of putting money first...
You've stuck with it since we were kids.
Actually, in first-tier cities,
Pet funerals have been a thing for years.
It's not exactly new.
But spending 200,000 for a pup's funeral...
This is definitely a first.
In a small place like Lecang,
with Great-Grandma Qimeng paying so much,
everyone must be fighting over it.
Dad was right about one thing.
If word gets out we did a dog's funeral,
who would trust you with their elders?
I was thinking...
Tell me.
What if we use Great-Grandma's order
to try
and see if we can get pet funerals going?
Didn't you tell us during the training?
Someone has to be the first to take the leap.
Right.
We have to be pioneers.
Xiaofang, let me tell you,
I've sorted everything out with my dad.
Come on, cheers.
Oh, really?
Then call your dad right now.
I'll confront him.
Honey,
you're living your life with me,
not with my dad.
Why do you always care about what he thinks?
Do you have any idea
that your Cousin Great-Grandaunt came?
Of course I do.
I begged for it in the family group chat.
I wanted to contribute
to my wife's career.
Zhou Fang, are you crazy?
I...
How am I crazy?
Brother-in-law,
what did I do wrong this time?
Zhou Fang,
sometimes doing nothing is a big mistake.
So what do I do now?
Go after her!
Xiaofang!
You scared the hell out of me.
I thought someone was trying to rob me.
Who'd steal your book?
You fall asleep the second you read.
When are you gonna change?
This is very complicated.
Did you know?
You went out for barbecue, didn't you?
And you didn't even bring any back for me.
You can smell that?
We got a huge 200,000 order today.
Xiaofang treated us.
200,000?
Who is so generous?
Do they need a professional mourner?
My market rate is 800.
I'll give you 400.
But you have to quote them 800.
You keep 400 as a kickback.
Are you serious?
Absolutely.
Deal.
Well, it's not a person.
It's a dog.
That won't work.
If I mourn for a dog,
what am I supposed to call it?
No, no way.
A dog is just too ridiculous.
I wouldn't be able to cry.
What's wrong?
Do you also think
a funeral for a dog is inappropriate?
A funeral for a dog...
In principle,
there's nothing inappropriate about it.
A dog is a life too.
They have parents too, after all.
Right?
When they arrive,
every life deserves a proper welcome.
When they leave,
every life deserves a proper farewell.
I just can't help but think how
a rich family's dog
is worth more than a poor person's life.
Don't you think?
Lan!
Come down and play mahjong!
Coming, coming!
Give me a second.
I'll be right down!
Take my glasses back inside.
Ancestors.
I, Chen Jianguo, failed to raise my kids.
That's why they're so rebellious.
Dad.
What is it?
Take a few steps to the door.
Stand there.
Open your mouth.
Did you taste anything?
Taste what?
Nothing but cold air.
With the current economy,
running a business is insanely competitive.
How many of our jobs actually make money?
Times have changed.
The industry needs to transition.
And our mindset needs to change too.
Our ancestors' rules can't be broken.
Dad, why are you coughing?
None of your business.
You must face the consequences yourself.
Uncle Chen.
Calm down, calm down.
About this pet funeral business,
I looked up some data last night.
I found out the scale of the pet economy
has already exceeded 400 billion.
And there are 100 million pet owners.
Three million pets pass away every year.
Based on data from smaller cities,
the pet funeral penetration rate is 3.6%.
Dad,
we have to keep up with the times.
What's a penetration rate?
Quick, explain it.
Simply put, out of every 100 pet owners,
four will choose pet funeral services.
You think just relying on this data
settles the ledger of life and death?
You're too naive.
You're right, Uncle Chen.
That's true.
But think about it,
don't the lives of cats and dogs matter too?
Everyone comes into this world pure,
shouldn't they leave with dignity too?
No matter what you say,
without rules, there is no order.
Rules
are the very foundation of our profession.
Our ancestors' rules can't be broken.
We aren't breaking them.
We still have reverence for life.
We still respect and memorialize the dead.
And we still bring comfort to the living.
I think Yiran makes a good point.
In business, you must pick up pennies,
while looking at the stars. She's right.
I'm speechless.
But,
what's trivial and what truly matters,
you need to get that straight.
Did Uncle Chen agree or not?
At least he didn't disown you.
Come help me count the money.
Come on.
You still need my help with this?
Just come here.
Such a huge scar,
why didn't you cover it up for them?
Isn't this what they asked for?
They wanted to keep their truest look.
Look at Tangtang.
She's gotten so thin.
She's nothing but skin and bones.
The poor child.
Lao Wu,
I don't pity them at all.
I actually think they're incredibly strong.
While we were shooting,
they almost fainted several times.
I kept telling them,
"Let's take a break.
Let's rest for a bit."
Do you know what they said?
They said
time is a luxury for them.
They wanted to shoot while still standing,
and get the photos done right away.
Those two kids are really pitiful.
It really proves the old saying,
A rope breaks at its thinnest point,
and bad luck always finds the unfortunate."
Wu Huilan!
When they come to pick out photos later,
if you keep wailing, we'll have a problem.
Keep your damn mouth shut.
Wumei!
Wumei.
Mei as in plum blossom.
Mei as in bad luck!
"Plum blossom," yeah right.
A real man doesn't fight a woman.
Alright, alright.
How about this.
Let's hang their photos
in the most prominent spot in our shop.
This way,
every customer who comes in
can see what their love looks like.
Sounds good.
Good idea.
Zhou Fang.
Aunt Huilan.
You guys take a seat first.
I'll show you the photos.
We brought you some fruit.
We picked these ourselves in the suburbs.
Great, great.
Have a taste, have a taste.
Try one right now.
This fruit looks delicious.
Let's sit down.
Let's look at the photos.
Okay.
Thank you.
This setting...
A beach in Europe.
Europe.
I guess we've been abroad now.
You two look
so real in these.
So beautiful.
Even the details...
It's like you've traveled the whole world.
It's beautiful.
There's more on the next page.
Look at the next ones.
Look at the lighting here.
Doesn't it look real?
That's our Xidongdong for you.
Is it too sour?
What are you crying for?
It's not sour, not sour.
It's delicious.
Coming to the last page.
This wedding...
The wedding venue.
You two look so handsome and beautiful.
I like this one.
That's Xidongdong for you.
That's Zhou Fang for you.
You know it.
Alright.
There's still more in the back.
Take a look.
Look back here.
These all belonged to Duoduo.
Take a look.
See if there's anything you can use.
Is this Duoduo's too?
This was his favorite music.
Let's play it at the funeral.
Brahms' String Quartet.
Yes.
Hey handsome,
you've got good taste.
To actually know this piece.
I know a thing or two.
Okay.
What I'm about to say,
you all need to write down.
First,
preserve Duoduo's best look.
Second,
I want a limited edition urn.
Inlaid with six diamonds.
Third,
pick a spot with the best feng shui.
I'll visit him in the future.
Okay.
Noted.
Are we doing a burial?
Is that a problem?
Miss Cousin Great-Grandaunt,
Well...
I'll add another 50,000.
You don't have to worry about that.
It's absolutely no problem.
All right.
Get to work.
We'll send Duoduo off in two days.
Two days?
If you think that's not enough time,
then you'd better hurry up.
Do I need to teach you that?
Two days...
200,000 sure isn't easy to earn.
It's 250,000.
For this price,
if she wanted the stars from the sky,
I'd get them for her.
Okay.
For the sake of the money.
Yiran,
can you use your superpower on dogs?
Yes.
Not only can I use it on dogs,
I can use it on you, too.
Then touch me.
Feel it.
Are you asking for it?
All right.
Even though I don't know
how a dog can understand classical music,
demanding clients are the best clients.
The classical music part is easy.
But this...
Duoduo's post-mortem makeup...
I don't know how to do it anyway.
Me neither.
Let's outsource it.
Here comes someone who can.
Such a great deal?
Then the 300,000 we invested last time...
won't we make a fortune?
They've raised the investment limit.
The annual interest rate jumped to 20%.
Everyone's scrambling for it.
I got this inside scoop.
Can you scrape together some more cash?
Let me tell you, this project...
I've been following it for a long time.
Hold on.
Mommy is on the phone with Uncle.
The little bit you invest now...
will yield a huge return later.
Sis.
This opportunity is so rare!
Borrow a bit more money.
We'll wait for the payout at year's end.
Yangyang is going to find Uncle Daren.
Stop hesitating!
Wait longer and the chance will slip away.
Brother.
I've already given you everything I have.
Where am I supposed to borrow money?
Yaya.
Our birdcage is fixed.
Soon we'll get to eat some yummy food.
Uncle Daren is amazing.
Isn't this the idiot from the barbershop?
Let go of Yaya!
Let Yaya go!
This bird is pretty fat.
If we roast it...
It's gonna taste absolutely killer.
Please don't eat Yaya!
Get on your knees and beg me.
Beg me!
Kneel. Come on.
Come on!
Kneel!
Hurry up!
Please don't eat Yaya!
Didn't your dad run away?
Sing 'Dad is the Best in the World'.
Dad is the best in the world...
A kid with a dad...
Not bad at all!
is like a treasure...
You really are a huge idiot.
You can just mortgage the house!
Once the investment makes money,
you can buy it back immediately!
Mortgage the house?
What if we lose it all?
Yangyang and I won't have a place to live.
Miss this good opportunity, and it's gone.
Think about it!
Once we make money,
whatever you want to buy for Yangyang,
you'll be able to buy it!
Stop thinking about it!
Slap yourself a hundred times.
Once you slap enough,
we'll give the bird
back to you.
I'm counting. Slap yourself hard!
Huge idiot!
What a huge idiot.
Slap!
A hundred times!
Alright.
I'll figure something out.
Great!
Yangyang
Have you seen Yangyang?
That kid.
Haven't seen him today.
Yangyang!
Can this bird really fly?
Let's find out.
Here.
Hold it tight.
What's it to you?
Get the hell out of here!
Who do you think you are?
Sticking your nose in our business.
Never been beaten by a real thug, huh?
Piss on the ground,
look at your reflection,
and you'll be enlightened.
Enlighten my ass!
Take out your phone.
Delete it.
Ow, ow, ow!
Hurry up!
Okay!
Ow, ow, ow!
I deleted it! I deleted it!
Bro, bro!
Get him!
Come here and give me a hand.
I pulled my groin, bro.
I can't walk.
You're totally useless.
Hanging out with you, seriously...
Let's go, let's go.
Easy, easy.
Is it in here?
Okay.
Yangyang!
Mom!
You disappeared the second I looked away.
Give me your hand.
Didn't I tell you?
Don't run off by yourself.
You scared me to death!
Mom.
What is it?
Someone picked on Yangyang and Yaya.
What are you doing?
Why are you picking on him?
It...
This man saved me.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry. I'm sorry.
It's fine.
I'm a good guy.
Who picked on you?
Yangyang is fine.
Don't be mad, Mom.
Thank you.
Thank you for saving Yangyang.
You're welcome.
It was nothing.
I'd like...
I'd like to ask...
this place in Chunguang Alley...
How do I get to Lijuan Barbershop?
Who are you?
Sit down.
Um, you...
"You" what?
Listen to me.
"Me" what?
What's with this and that?
Watch me.
I...
Spit it out!
What do you think?
Feel like a new man?
You look handsome.
Does it look good?
It looks good.
Really good.
But I didn't come for a haircut.
You didn't come for a haircut?
Then what are you here for?
Yiran told me to come.
To learn the trade from you.
That mother and daughter duo,
always making trouble for me all day.
Like a couple of debt collectors.
Let me tell you, Ah Min,
if it weren't for the fact
that you helped Yangyang,
I wouldn't teach you for free.
You know?
Did you hear me?
G-
Got it, got it.
Come over here.
Okay.
Stand here.
Watch closely.
In a minute,
follow what I teach you
and try it yourself.
Just treat this fur as human hair.
See that?
After you comb it smooth,
with this hand,
just snip.
Snip.
See?
Just don't cut your hand.
Got it?
Got it.
Yangyang!
How many times have I told you?
When you play with your blocks,
you leave them everywhere.
What if customers come in?
Can't you clean them up?
This kid, seriously.
Um...
I... I... I...
I'll practice a bit.
I'm gonna go practice.
Practice a bit.
Take this big horse.
Cut it.
Thank you,
Uncle Amin.
Why is your face red?
No, no.
It's not.
Hurry.
Uncle Amin.
Will you come play with me again?
I will.
That's great!
Amin.
You seem pretty handy with those tools.
They're yours.
For me?
Thanks.
I didn't cook anything,
so I won't ask you to stay.
No.
That doesn't matter.
I... I...
I don't eat dinner.
No, no.
I mean...
I eat vegetarian at night.
No...
It's getting late.
I should go back.
Bye.
Let's go.
Yangyang likes Uncle Amin.
I like Uncle Amin.
Then do you like Sister Yiran
or Uncle Amin?
I like both!
This is the place.
Boss, take a look at this plot.
Round on the outside, square inside.
An open and spacious front.
Mountains in the back.
A river in the front.
Surrounded by mountains and water.
Right next to the city.
Accessible from all directions.
If buried here,
your dog
will surely be blessed in its next life.
Alright.
I'm buying it.
Xiaofang, sign it.
Great-Grandma,
please sign.
Duoduo loves this blanket the most.
He can't even sleep without it.
Excuse me,
could you use this one?
Duoduo has a lot of fur.
It tangles a lot.
I'm afraid that one will hurt him.
Okay.
Thank you.
Why don't you brush him one last time?
It means more when you do it.
He loved it most when I rubbed his belly.
Sometimes, if I just waved at him,
he'd come right over,
rolling over to show his belly.
Whenever I petted him,
he'd wag his tail happily.
But I'll never see that again.
Life is but a fleeting moment.
Such a brief existence.
How can we ever forget?
All things have a spirit.
All bonds are guided by fate.
He'll have a peaceful journey.
Thank you.
Duoduo.
Rest in peace.
Thank you.
My condolences to you too.
We're ready.
Honored guests,
family and friends.
Today, we are gathered here
to remember our mutual friend,
Duoduo.
Duoduo
was not just a pet,
but also family.
Next,
let's welcome Duoduo's parent,
Ms. Qimeng, to deliver the eulogy.
Thank you.
Hello, everyone.
I'm Duoduo's mom.
Thank you all for taking the time
to attend Duoduo's memorial service.
Ten years ago,
when Duoduo first came to me,
he was so tiny back then,
and so timid.
Thank you for being with me for ten years
and for the joy you've brought me.
I also hope everyone
will cherish their loved ones.
Thank you.
I'm sure Duoduo would want you to be happy.
May Duoduo run on the grass in heaven,
happy and free.
Please pay your final respects to Duoduo.
Do not stand at my grave and weep.
I am not there.
I do not sleep.
I am a thousand winds that blow.
I am the softly falling snow.
I am the golden waves of ripened grain.
I am the gentle autumn rain.
I will soar above the river,
As a flock of birds taking flight.
When you fall asleep bathed in moonlight,
I am the gentle stars in the night sky.
Do not stand at my grave and cry.
I am not there.
I did not die.
Please observe a moment of silence.
Great-Grandma Qimeng,
we made something for Duoduo.
This is some fur we clipped from Duoduo.
Keep it as a memento.
Thank you.
Thank you for sending him off with care.
His journey won't be lonely.
I'm sorry.
Tears are a privilege of the living.
Tears can't reach him on the other side,
but he can feel the echoes.
Everything you did for him,
your love for him,
he will know it all.
Thank you.
Cousin Great-Grandaunt,
Actually,
when we tallied up the funeral costs,
it really didn't cost that much.
Please take the rest of this money back.
You keep it.
Think of it as a deposit I left here,
a fund for pet funerals.
I trust you'll put it to good use.
We will.
Xiaofang,
that brat Zhou Fang...
he's so lucky to have you.
Min,
what did you think of the funeral?
Duoduo's funeral...
How did we do?
Every life, no matter how small,
has its meaning and value.
And deserves a proper farewell.
Baixi,
you did great.
This might be a new start for Xiaoxitian.
I'll head over first.
Dad.
Why are you here?
You didn't even tell us you were coming.
What?
Can't I come?
I came to see
if you've ruined Xiaoxitian's reputation.
Well?
Did we?
Not this time.
But that doesn't mean you won't next time.
You've got a hair here.
When your old man was twelve,
I followed your grandpa into this trade.
Now,
the world is changing too fast.
I'm getting old.
I'm no use anymore.
But you've grown up.
Go on.
Go do what you love.
Just go.
Then wait for me a sec.